Guide to the Grand Street Publications, Inc. Records
Rare Book and Manuscript Library Columbia University Libraries
Grand Street Publications, Inc. records,
1981-2004.
Grand Street Publications, Inc. Records
53.85 linear feet (47 legal sized document boxes; 18 record cartons, legal sized; 13 record cartons, letter sized).
Columbia University Rare Book and Manuscript Library, Butler Library, New York, NY 10027.
MS#0508
4078372
These records contain the editorial, production and correspondence files of Grand Street, a New York literary quarterly founded by Ben Sonnenberg Jr. in 1981 and published through 2004. Throughout its two decades, Grand Street prided itself on nurturing authors and presenting a smart and eclectic mix of contemporary poetry, fiction, art and journalism. The bulk of this collection consists of annotated manuscripts, proofs and correspondence related to the magazine: featured writers include Anne Carson, Arthur Coleman Danto, Jonathan Franzen, Dennis Hopper, Ted Hughes, Norman Mailer, Susan Minot, Toni Morrison, Alice Munro, Orhan Pamuk, Salman Rushide, Edward Said and David Foster Wallace. Production files related to the magazine's operation are also housed within these records and these files include contracts, press and publicity files, design ideas and materials pertaining to Grand Street's attempts to rebrand itself as an online only magazine in the 2000s.
Historical Note
Ben Sonnenberg founded Grand Street in 1981 and edited the magazine through the 1980s, defining its important role in New York's literary landscape. Sonnenberg capitalized upon his affluent New York upbringing and friendships with writers such as Ted Hughes to forge a "little magazine" in the tradition of The Parisian Review and Granta. Devoted to contemporary literature and politics, Grand Street was published quarterly and featured an enticing and eclectic selection of poetry, fiction and journalism.
Sonnenberg was a devoted and nurturing editor, striving to recompense writers financially and artistically; many writers were pleased by the generous fees and detailed editorial advice that Grand Street offered them. Sonnenberg also created a literary circle, hosting dinners with contributors in his Riverside Drive apartment and worked strenuously to promote new talent, including Anne Carson and Susan Minot. Carson attested to the close mentorship Sonnenberg provided, writing to him that he was "always in the back of my thoughts like a piece of chocolate saved in the corner of the cupboard all through Lent." Other writers featured throughout the 1980s include Grover Amen, Arthur Coleman Danto, Ted Hughes, W.S. Merwin, Alice Munro, Joyce Carol Oates, Laura Riding, Edward Said and Virgil Thomson.
Upon Sonnenberg's retirement in 1989, Jean Stein took over Grand Street's lease as editor. Stein expanded the magazine's portfolio to include more international authors and work by contemporary artists. Featured artists were given a high-quality spread in Grand Street and these portfolios were usually accompanied by a short critical commentary. The increasing presence of art assisted another transition in the 1990s, when Grand Street became theme-driven from issue 48 onwards. These themes were often rather broad, allowing for interesting approaches from the featured artists and writers. Themes included Games (Issue 51), Fetishes (Issue 53), Dirt (Issue 57), Fire (Issue 67) and Berlin (Issue 69).
Ironically, Grand Street's initial theme--Oblivion--was strangely prophetic for the path of print journalism after the millennium. Encouraged by economic exigencies, Stein made the bold move of establishing Grand Street as a "state of the art" online magazine (with one print issue each year) in 2000. As part of this transition, Grand Street redesigned its website and put much of its artistic and literary archives online. Despite this stylish website and continued crop of interesting artists and writers, Grand Street struggled in its new home and attempted to revert back to a print journal in 2003. Having lost momentum and faced with an increasingly difficult market for journals, Grand Street ceased publication after the release of its 73rd Issue (Delusions) in the Fall of 2004.
Scope and Content
The bulk of these records comprise annotated manuscripts, correspondence and editorial and production files for Grand Street. Manuscripts include multiple annotated drafts of poems, articles and fiction as well as final proofs. Professional correspondence related to these files with authors, editor and agents is also contained within the records. Other materials include art files, photographs and slides, press clippings and financial documents.
Arrangement
This collection is arranged in three series.
Series I: Editorial Files, 1982-2004
Subseries I.1: Literary Files, 1982-1990
Subseries I.2: Art Files, 1991-2004
Subseries I.3: Author Files, 1989-2004
Subseries I.4: Supplementary Editorial Material, 1990-2003
Series II: Correspondence, 1981-2000
Subseries II.1: Authors, 1981-1990
Subseries II.2: Agents and Publishers, 1981-2000
Series III: Production, 1990-2004
Subjects
Carson, Anne, 1950-; Hughes, Ted, 1930-1998.; Minot, Susan.; Said, Edward, W.; Sonnenberg, Benjamin, 1901-1978.; Stein, Jean, 1947-; Grand Street.; Literature--Periodicals.; Little Magazines--Periodicals.; Publishers and publishing.; Essays.; Fiction.; Manuscripts (literary).; Photographs.; Poems.
Access Restrictions
This collection has no restrictions.
This collection is located off-site. You will need to request this material at least twenty-four (24) hours in advance to use the collection in the Rare Book and Manuscript Library reading room.
Gift of Philip Morris, Inc., 1984.
Gift of Grand Street Publications, Inc., 1986, 1987, 1989, 1991, and 2004.
Selected Related Material at Columbia
Benjamin Sonnenberg Papers, 1956-2001 Columbia University, Rare Book & Manuscript Library.
- Series I: Editorial Files, 1982-2004
  This large series holds materials related to the artistic content of Grand Street, including drafts and galleys of poems, essays and stories; images by featured artists; unused submissions and ideas for future stories. Grand Street's original filing order has been preserved: in the 1980s editorial files were arranged chronologically by magazine issue while from the 1990s on these same materials were sorted alphabetically by author. Similarly, volume numbers reflect Grand Street's own arrangement: during the 1980s, the journal classified each quarterly issue as part of a yearly volume while from the 1990s onwards, each issue was given its own number.
  - Subseries 1: Literary Files,1982-1990
    Editorial materials from Grand Street's initial years, organized chronologically by issue, are contained in this subseries. The files for each issue contain general editorial materials as well as drafts of all artistic materials (short stories, poems, essays). Within each issue, these materials are organized by ascending page number within the publication: an index appears at the start of each issue. Edits are not restricted to copy-editing and sometimes denote significant artistic changes.
    - Volume I, 1982-1983
      - Number 2, (2 Folders) (Box 1, Folder 29 to 30)
      - Number 3, (3 Folders) (Box 2, Folder 1 to 3)
      - Number 4, (2 Folders) (Box 2, Folder 4 to 5)
      - Number 4, (2 Folders) (Box 3, Folder 1 to 2)
    - Volume II, 1982-1983
      - Number 1, (4 Folders) (Box 3, Folder 3 to 6)
      - Number 1, (2 Folders) (Box 4, Folder 1 to 2)
      - Number 2, (4 Folders) (Box 4, Folder 3 to 6)
      - Number 2, (4 Folders) (Box 5, Folder 1 to 4)
      - Number 3, (5 Folders) (Box 5, Folder 5 to 9)
      - Number 3, (5 Folders) (Box 6, Folder 1 to 5)
      - Number 4, (3 Folders) (Box 6, Folder 6 to 8)
      - Number 4, (5 Folders) (Box 7, Folder 1 to 5)
    - Volume III, 1983-1984
      - Number 1, (5 Folders) (Box 7, Folder 6 to 10)
      - Number 1, (4 Folders) (Box 8, Folder 1 to 4)
      - Number 2, (3 Folders) (Box 8, Folder 5 to 7)
      - Number 2, (7 Folders) (Box 9, Folder 1 to 7)
      - Number 3, (2 Folders) (Box 9, Folder 8 to 9)
      - Number 3, (7 Folders) (Box 10, Folder 1 to 7)
      - Number 4 (Box 10, Folder 8)
      - Number 4, (7 Folders) (Box 11, Folder 1 to 7)
    - Volume IV, 1984-1985
      - Number 1 (Box 11, Folder 8)
      - Number 1, (8 Folders) (Box 12, Folder 1 to 8)
      - Number 2 (8 of 9 Folders) (Box 13, Folder 1 to 8)
      - Number 2 (1 of 9 Folders) (Box 14, Folder 1)
      - Number 3 (5 of 7 Folders) (Box 14, Folder 2 to 6)
      - Number 3 (2 of 7 Folders) (Box 15, Folder 1 to 2)
      - Number 4, (4 Folders) (Box 15, Folder 3 to 6)
      - Number 4, (4 Folders) (Box 16, Folder 1 to 4)
    - Volume V, 1985-1986
      - Number 1, (2 Folders) (Box 16, Folder 5 to 6)
      - Number 1, (7 Folders) (Box 17, Folder 1 to 7)
      - Number 1 (Box 18, Folder 1)
      - Number 2, (5 Folders) (Box 18, Folder 2 to 6)
      - Number 2, (4 Folders) (Box 19, Folder 1 to 4)
      - Number 3, (3 Folders) (Box 19, Folder 5 to 7)
      - Number 3, (4 Folders) (Box 20, Folder 1 to 4)
      - Number 4, (2 Folders) (Box 20, Folder 5 to 6)
      - Number 4, (5 Folders) (Box 21, Folder 1 to 5)
      - Number 4 (Box 22, Folder 1)
    - Volume VI, 1986-1987
      - Number 1, (5 Folders) (Box 22, Folder 2 to 6)
      - Number 1, (3 Folders) (Box 23, Folder 1 to 3)
      - Number 2, (4 Folders) (Box 23, Folder 4 to 7)
      - Number 2, (5 Folders) (Box 24, Folder 1 to 5)
      - Number 3, (2 Folders) (Box 24, Folder 6 to 7)
      - Number 3, (6 Folders) (Box 25, Folder 1 to 6)
      - Number 4, (7 Folders) (Box 26, Folder 1 to 7)
      - Number 4 (Box 27, Folder 1)
    - Volume VII, 1987-1988
      - Number 1, (5 Folders) (Box 27, Folder 2 to 6)
      - Number 1, (4 Folders) (Box 28, Folder 1 to 4)
      - Number 2, (3 Folders) (Box 28, Folder 5 to 7)
      - Number 2, (7 Folders) (Box 29, Folder 1 to 7)
      - Number 2 (Box 30, Folder 1)
      - Number 3, (5 Folders) (Box 30, Folder 2 to 6)
      - Number 3, (4 Folders) (Box 31, Folder 1 to 4)
      - Number 4, (3 Folders) (Box 31, Folder 5 to 7)
      - Number 4, (6 Folders) (Box 32, Folder 1 to 6)
    - Volume VIII, 1988- 1989
      - Number 1, (6 Folders) (Box 33, Folder 1 to 6)
      - Number 1, (2 Folders) (Box 34, Folder 1 to 2)
      - Number 2, (4 Folders) (Box 34, Folder 3 to 6)
      - Number 2, (4 Folders) (Box 35, Folder 1 to 4)
      - Number 3, (2 Folders) (Box 35, Folder 5 to 6)
      - Number 3, (5 Folders) (Box 36, Folder 1 to 5)
      - Number 3 (Box 37, Folder 1)
      - Number 4, (6 Folders) (Box 37, Folder 2 to 7)
      - Number 4, (4 Folders) (Box 38, Folder 1 to 4)
    - Volume IX, 1989-1990
      - Number 1, (2 Folders) (Box 38, Folder 5 to 6)
      - Number 1, (6 Folders) (Box 39, Folder 1 to 6)
      - Number 1 (Box 40, Folder 1)
      - Number 2, (5 Folders) (Box 40, Folder 2 to 6)
      - Number 2 (Box 41, Folder 1)
      - Number 3, (5 Folders) (Box 41, Folder 2 to 6)
      - Number 3, (5 Folders) (Box 42, Folder 1 to 5)
  - Subseries I.2: Art Files, 1991-2004
    When Jean Stein took over from Ben Sonnenberg as editor and publisher in 1990, Grand Street evolved to include visual art alongside literary work. Materials relating to the art and artists featured in Grand Street comprise this subseries. Materials are arranged chronologically by issue and are then divided alphabetically by author or artist. Many artists' work was supplemented by a critical essay. (In arranging this subseries, the original filing system has been preserved, so that these essays are sometimes listed by author and sometimes by artist.) Each issue includes a general folder featuring editorial correspondence and ideas about the artists.
    - General--Cover Images, 1991 (Box 64, Folder 31)
    - Issue 46, 1993
      - General (Box 64, Folder 32)
      - Balk, Dennis (Box 64, Folder 33)
      - Calvino, Italo (Box 64, Folder 34)
      - Chamoiseau, Patrick (Box 64, Folder 35)
      - Cross, Brian--Rap Interviews (Box 64, Folder 36)
      - CPLY--William Copley (Box 64, Folder 37)
      - Johnson, Uwe (Box 64, Folder 38)
      - Olney, Richard (Box 64, Folder 39)
      - Richardson, Tony (Box 64, Folder 40)
      - Rubin, Nancy (Box 65, Folder 1)
      - Toer, Pramoedya Ananta (Box 65, Folder 2)
      - Veronisi, Sandro (Box 65, Folder 3)
      - Vollman--Navajo and Hopi Story (Box 65, Folder 4)
      - Wallace, David Foster (Box 65, Folder 5)
    - Issue 47, 1993-1994
      - Research and Development (Box 65, Folder 6)
      - Althusser, Louis (Box 65, Folder 7)
      - Bloom Barbara (Box 65, Folder 8)
      - Galan, Julio (Box 65, Folder 9)
      - Genet, Jean (Box 65, Folder 10)
      - Jones, Lloyd (Box 65, Folder 11)
      - Jouvet, Louis (Box 65, Folder 12)
      - MacKay, Shena (Box 65, Folder 13)
      - Millhauser, Steven (Box 65, Folder 14)
      - Montgomery (Box 65, Folder 15)
      - Said, Edward (Box 65, Folder 16)
      - Tanizaki, Junichiro (Box 65, Folder 17)
      - Unger, K.S. (Box 65, Folder 18)
    - Issue 48--Obilvion, 1993-1994
      - General, (4 Folders) (Box 65, Folder 19 to 22)
      - Buzzi, Aldo (Box 65, Folder 23)
      - Boll, Heinrich (Box 65, Folder 24)
      - Hilbig, Wolfgang (Box 65, Folder 25)
      - Palliser, Charles (Box 65, Folder 26)
      - Sorokin, Vladimir (Box 65, Folder 27)
      - Steinberg, Saul (Box 65, Folder 28)
      - Thorne, Kip (Box 65, Folder 29)
      - Weiner, Lawrence (Box 65, Folder 30)
    - Issue 49--Hollywood, 1993-1994
      - General, (2 Folders) (Box 65, Folder 31 to 32)
      - Deen, Georgannie (Box 65, Folder 33)
      - Faust, Daniel (Box 65, Folder 34)
      - Herrmann, Bernard (Box 65, Folder 35)
      - Hilton, Als (Box 65, Folder 36)
      - Pettibon, Raymond (Box 65, Folder 37)
      - Rohauer, Raymond (Box 65, Folder 38)
      - Ruscha, Edward (Box 65, Folder 39)
      - Southern, Terry (Box 65, Folder 40)
      - Ten Commandments (Box 65, Folder 41)
      - Van Peebles, James (Box 65, Folder 42)
      - Welles, Orson (Box 65, Folder 43)
    - Issue 50--Models, 1994
      - General (Box 65, Folder 44)
      - Als, Hilton (Box 65, Folder 45)
      - Bowery, Leigh (Box 65, Folder 46)
      - Chiapas (Box 65, Folder 47)
      - Doran, Anne (Box 65, Folder 48)
      - Fiegenbaum, Mitchell (Box 65, Folder 49)
      - Greenbelt (Box 65, Folder 50)
      - Hopper, Dennis (Box 65, Folder 51)
      - Hopper, Dennis and Quentin Tarantino (Box 65, Folder 52)
      - Jones, Kim (Box 65, Folder 53)
      - McCarthy, Paul (Box 65, Folder 54)
      - Matisse (Box 65, Folder 55)
      - Sans, Jeremy (Box 65, Folder 56)
      - Sieverding, Katharina (Box 65, Folder 57)
    - Issue 51--New York, 1994- 1995
      - General (Box 66, Folder 1)
      - Baudrillard, Jean (Box 66, Folder 2)
      - Bonk, Ecke (Box 66, Folder 3)
      - Burden, Chris (Box 66, Folder 4)
      - Faurer, Louis (Box 66, Folder 5)
      - Friedman, B.H. (Box 66, Folder 6)
      - Gangs (Box 66, Folder 7)
      - Hammons, David (Box 66, Folder 8)
      - James, Darius (Box 66, Folder 9)
      - Lawler, Louise (Box 66, Folder 10)
      - Moore, Michael (Box 66, Folder 11)
      - Morton, Margaret (Box 66, Folder 12)
      - Oe, Kenzaburo (Box 66, Folder 13)
      - Prince, Richard (Box 66, Folder 14)
      - Virilio (Box 66, Folder 15)
      - Williams, Terry (Box 66, Folder 16)
      - Williams, Robert (Box 66, Folder 17)
    - Issue 52--Games, 1994-1995
      - General, (2 Folders) (Box 66, Folder 18 to 19)
      - Anderson, Olie (Box 66, Folder 20)
      - Benjamin, Walter (Box 66, Folder 21)
      - Chess (Box 66, Folder 22)
      - Defeo, Jay (Box 66, Folder 23)
      - Hopper, Dennis (Box 66, Folder 24)
      - Oursler, Tony (Box 66, Folder 25)
      - Santino, Peter (Box 66, Folder 26)
      - Schumann, Christian (Box 66, Folder 27)
    - Issue 53--Fetishes, 1994-1995
      - General (Box 66, Folder 39)
      - Bartlett, Morton (Box 66, Folder 28)
      - Evans, Walker (Box 66, Folder 29)
      - Flanagan, Bob (Box 66, Folder 30)
      - Kusama, Yayoi (Box 66, Folder 31)
      - Matlock, Jann (Box 66, Folder 32)
      - Newton, Helmut (Box 66, Folder 33)
      - Ray, Man (Box 66, Folder 34)
      - Rodriguez and De Cesare (Box 66, Folder 35)
      - Sellin, Birger (Box 66, Folder 36)
      - Steinbach, Haim (Box 66, Folder 37)
      - Waters, John (Box 66, Folder 38)
    - Issue 54--Space, 1995
      - General (Box 66, Folder 40)
      - Acconci, Vito (Box 66, Folder 41)
      - Davis, Jomo (Box 66, Folder 42)
      - Morton, Margaret (Box 66, Folder 43)
      - Pippin, Steven (Box 66, Folder 44)
      - Space and UFOS (Box 66, Folder 45)
      - Turrell, James (Box 66, Folder 46)
      - Ukeles, Mierle (Box 66, Folder 47)
    - Issue 55--Egos, 1995
      - General (Box 66, Folder 48)
      - Als, Hilton (Box 66, Folder 49)
      - Bellen, Martine (Box 66, Folder 50)
      - Berlin, Bridgid (Box 66, Folder 51)
      - Bochner, Mel (Box 66, Folder 52)
      - Davey, Moyra (Box 66, Folder 53)
      - Drucker, J.S. (Box 66, Folder 54)
      - Hopper, Dennis (Box 66, Folder 55)
      - Kienholz, Edward (Box 66, Folder 56)
      - Schnabel. Julian (Box 66, Folder 57)
      - Tisdale, Danny (Box 66, Folder 58)
      - Waters, John (Box 66, Folder 59)
    - Issue 56--Dreams, 1995
      - General (Box 66, Folder 60)
      - Bunuel, Luis (Box 66, Folder 61)
      - Hecker, Rachel (Box 66, Folder 62)
      - Heizer, Michael (Box 66, Folder 63)
      - Herms, George (Box 67, Folder 1)
      - La, Adobe (Box 67, Folder 2)
      - Plains Indians (Box 67, Folder 3)
      - Ruscha, Edward (Box 67, Folder 4)
      - Shaw, Jim (Box 67, Folder 5)
      - Southern, Terry (Box 67, Folder 6)
      - Spruce Goose (Box 67, Folder 7)
      - Stockhausen, K.H. (Box 67, Folder 8)
      - Zinacantan Dreams (Box 67, Folder 9)
    - Issue 57--Dirt, 1995-1996
      - General, (2 Folders) (Box 67, Folder 10 to 11)
      - Anger, Kenneth (Box 67, Folder 12)
      - Clay, Langdon (Box 67, Folder 13)
      - Friedman, Tom (Box 67, Folder 14)
      - Genet, Jean (Box 67, Folder 15)
      - Guibert, Herve (Box 67, Folder 16)
      - Guignol, Grand (Box 67, Folder 17)
      - Kelley, Mike (Box 67, Folder 18)
      - Koolhaas, Rem (Box 67, Folder 19)
      - Rockman, Alexis (Box 67, Folder 20)
    - Issue 58--Disguises, 1996-1997
      - General (Box 67, Folder 21)
      - Changeaux, Jean-Pierre (Box 67, Folder 22)
      - De Maria, Walter (Box 67, Folder 23)
      - Duchamp, Marcel, (2 Folders) (Box 67, Folder 24 to 25)
      - Gajdusek (Box 67, Folder 26)
      - Hoch, Hannah (Box 67, Folder 27)
      - Houston, Angelica (Box 67, Folder 28)
      - Molinier, Pierre (Box 67, Folder 29)
      - Pettinbone, Richard (Box 67, Folder 30)
      - Sherman, Cindy (Box 67, Folder 31)
      - Walker, Kara (Box 67, Folder 32)
      - Waters, John (Box 67, Folder 33)
    - Issue 59--Time, 1996-1997
      - General (Box 67, Folder 34)
      - Art Charts (Box 67, Folder 35)
      - CPLY--also known as William Copley (Box 67, Folder 36)
      - Davis, Mike (Box 67, Folder 37)
      - Gysin, Brion (Box 67, Folder 38)
      - Kabakov, Ilya (Box 67, Folder 39)
      - Marey, Etienne (Box 67, Folder 40)
      - Misrach, Richard (Box 67, Folder 41)
      - Rodriguez, Spain (Box 68, Folder 1)
      - Szarkowski, John (Box 68, Folder 2)
    - Issue 60--Paranoia, 1997
      - General (Box 68, Folder 3)
      - Artaud, Antonin (Box 68, Folder 4)
      - Cronenberg, David (Box 68, Folder 5)
      - Dali, Salvador (Box 68, Folder 6)
      - Fend, Peter (Box 68, Folder 7)
      - Kovenatsky, Vladimir (Box 68, Folder 8)
      - Laffoley, Paul (Box 68, Folder 9)
      - Moers, Denny (Box 68, Folder 10)
      - Madore Michael--Sanford Winslow--Melvin “Milky” Way (Box 68, Folder 11)
      - Muller, H.A. (Box 68, Folder 12)
      - Piper, Adrian (Box 68, Folder 13)
      - Sachs, Tom (Box 68, Folder 14)
      - Shaw, Fiona (Box 68, Folder 15)
      - Survival Research Laboratories (Box 68, Folder 16)
    - Issue 61--All-American, 1996-1997
      - General, (2 Folders) (Box 68, Folder 17 to 18)
      - Benedit, Luis (Box 68, Folder 19)
      - Cardoso, Maria (Box 68, Folder 20)
      - Davis, Lynn (Box 68, Folder 21)
      - Durham, Jimmie (Box 68, Folder 22)
      - Ferrez, Marc (Box 68, Folder 23)
      - Graham, Rodney (Box 68, Folder 24)
      - Herran, Juan Fernando (Box 68, Folder 25)
      - Kcho (Box 68, Folder 26)
      - Lovett, John/Codagnone, Alessandro (Box 68, Folder 27)
      - Mendieta, Ana (Box 68, Folder 28)
      - Mesa-Bains (Box 68, Folder 29)
      - Navigation (Box 68, Folder 30)
      - Orozco, Gabriel (Box 68, Folder 31)
      - Ortiz-Torres, Ruben (Box 68, Folder 32)
      - Paradise (Box 68, Folder 33)
      - Parcero, Tantiana (Box 68, Folder 34)
      - Pina, Manuel (Box 68, Folder 35)
      - Restrepo, Jose Alejandro (Box 68, Folder 36)
      - Salcedo, Doris (Box 68, Folder 37)
      - Welling, Jim (Box 68, Folder 38)
      - Vega, Sergio (Box 68, Folder 39)
    - Issue 62--Identity, 1997
      - General (Box 68, Folder 40)
      - Desoto, Lewis (Box 68, Folder 41)
      - Dittborn, Eugenio (Box 68, Folder 42)
      - Embargo (Box 69, Folder 1)
      - Fan Tutte, Cosi (Box 69, Folder 2)
      - Hatoum, Mona (Box 69, Folder 3)
      - Mastroianni, Marcello (Box 69, Folder 4)
      - Mekas, Jonas (Box 69, Folder 5)
      - Mereweather, Charles (Box 69, Folder 6)
      - Milagros de la Torre (Box 69, Folder 7)
      - Neshat, Shirin (Box 69, Folder 8)
      - Osorio, Pepon (Box 69, Folder 9)
      - Rauschenberg, Robert (Box 69, Folder 10)
      - Ray, Charles--Includes two Cassette Tapes (Box 69, Folder 11)
      - Renno, Rosangela (Box 69, Folder 12)
      - Rulfo, Juan (Box 69, Folder 13)
      - Sundaram, Vivian (Box 69, Folder 14)
      - Tarn, Nathaniel (Box 69, Folder 15)
    - Issue 63--Crossing the Line, 1997-1998
      - General (Box 69, Folder 16)
      - Abramovic, Marina (Box 69, Folder 17)
      - Bennett, Gordon (Box 69, Folder 18)
      - Clark, Lygia (Box 69, Folder 19)
      - Evans, George (Box 69, Folder 20)
      - Genzken, Isa (Box 69, Folder 21)
      - Ladda, Justin (Box 69, Folder 22)
      - Losang Chogyen, Pema (Box 69, Folder 23)
      - Maysles, Rebekah (Box 69, Folder 24)
      - Mengbo, Feng (Box 69, Folder 25)
      - Mobus, Christinane (Box 69, Folder 26)
      - Mondrian, Piet (Box 69, Folder 27)
      - Morton, Margaret (Box 69, Folder 28)
      - Varese (Box 69, Folder 29)
      - Waters, John (Box 69, Folder 30)
    - Issue 64--Memory, 1998
      - General (Box 69, Folder 31)
      - Calle, Sophie (Box 69, Folder 32)
      - Doherty, Willie (Box 69, Folder 33)
      - Kramer, Jane (Box 69, Folder 34)
      - Marker, Chris (Box 69, Folder 35)
      - Meireles, Cildo (Box 69, Folder 36)
      - Mofokene, Santu (Box 69, Folder 37)
      - Murch, Walter (Box 69, Folder 38)
      - Nagy, Peter (Box 69, Folder 39)
      - Ristelhueber, Sophie (Box 69, Folder 40)
      - Smith, Tony (Box 69, Folder 41)
      - Spero, Nancy (Box 70, Folder 1)
      - Vanitas (Box 70, Folder 2)
    - Issue 65--Trouble, 1998
      - General (Box 70, Folder 3)
      - Algeria (Box 70, Folder 4)
      - Bourgeois, Louise (Box 70, Folder 5)
      - Burrows, Larry (Box 70, Folder 6)
      - Ionesco, Eugene (Box 70, Folder 7)
      - Lebel, Jean-Jacques (Box 70, Folder 8)
      - Mann, Thomas (Box 70, Folder 9)
      - Medalla. David (Box 70, Folder 10)
      - Murakami, Takashi (Box 70, Folder 11)
      - Rambow, Inge (Box 70, Folder 12)
      - Taylor-Wood, Sam (Box 70, Folder 13)
      - Westerman, H.C. (Box 70, Folder 14)
      - Wodiczko, Krzysztof (Box 70, Folder 15)
    - Issue 66--Secrets, 1998
      - Bauer, Manuel (Box 70, Folder 16)
      - Brook, Peter (Box 70, Folder 17)
      - Cornell, Joseph (Box 70, Folder 18)
      - Dellschau, C.A.A. (Box 70, Folder 19)
      - Herrera, Arturo (Box 70, Folder 20)